VueDC is an idea that Ben and I had long running. So my
name is Christian Guirreri and I met some
of you as you came in
I'm a Senior Front-end Developer here on
JavaScript mainly. Ben Hong, Senior UI
Engineer, so he's going to be
speaking today and he's going to going over
a 101 on VueJS. Ben really
spearheaded this event, honestly he
really made it happen, so looking forward
to it and we're just really happy to have so
many people here. So why VueDC? We
didn't see that anyone else had a
Vue DC specifically and Politico spent
a lot of time, probably the past year to
looking at different JavaScript
frameworks and we've really kind of
narrowed down on Vue. We have
used a few different ones for a few
different products but our best products
I think were probably done in Vue. We do a
lot of native
JavaScript as well like we're trying to
trim down as much as possible but Vue
has been a really nice framework really
nice structure and been really
dependable for us. So we've kind of
decided to use that in the future. We could
easily have a talk I think on
comparing some of the frameworks and why
we've chosen Vue. We've kind of started
this group just to initiate the
discussion, have meetups like this one
where it's just you know introductory
to get people interested but
also more advanced topics obviously are
going to be coming. So VueConf, a few
announcements, since we should like all
meetups, should do the announcements thing,
VueConf US is coming up highly recommend
going all the famous people are going to
be there. [Where is it?] It is in New Orleans in March
So there's a workshop day on March
26th Monday, and then the conference is
Tuesday and Wednesday March 27 to 28.
So last year they did the first
official Vue conference I don't know
what makes it official I guess Evan
You is probably involved in that
official title but that was in Poland
and it's not here but there was a
YouTube channel that you can find I
there's a YouTube channel that you can
find that has all of the all of the
talks so we hope to see you there Ben
and I will both definitely be there so
sign up. So the next meetup is going to be
by me it'll be more of 201 it will sort
of continue a lot of what Ben is going
over today that's kind of how I like to
see see things going especially in
introductory phases but they're probably
fun so we hope you can all come back
with that and obviously any interest in
speaking come to Ben and me we're
definitely interested in hearing your
thoughts about any future meetups any
future talks stuff that you guys are
doing at your companies and if you need
any help like crafting a presentation
just reach out to us at vuejsdc@gmail.com
[Music]
We are interested in getting sponsors. We
want to make this a pretty big deal in
the area so you know you know of anybody
who's willing to sponsor either venue or
food or anything like that again reach
out to Ben or myself
but today's gold sponsor is Politico and
so I'd like to introduce you to Maria
Harrigan
she is a Talent Acquisition Manager at
Politico. Hi everyone. I'm so excited I get a whole slide
I know you didn't come to hear me talk and I don't always sound
like this so please bear with me start
like hacking up a long but I'm super
excited that Politico technology cares
so much about technology that they
wanted to start their own Meetup and
it's really exciting to be a part of it
from an HR and talent acquisition
standpoint I love being in recruiting
and helping with tech recruiting is it I
get to live vicariously through you people
that do really cool stuff but of course
I have to do the shameless plug about
Politico and I know a lot of people
think they probably hire a lot of
journalists or I get like "Oh you work at Politico
you must be a reporter and I'm like no
I'm in HR but we also have a really
awesome technology team and I would love
for you guys to think about maybe some
career Politico at some point online or
even just keeping in touch with me I
left out my business cards by the pizza
if you want to pick it up connect with
me on LinkedIn. You definitely don't have to. The
other thing is if you guys are like
putting this stuff on social we'd love
for you to tweet at us or tag us on
social @politicocareers
So with that said it's all I got
[Music]
all right
so as Chris mentioned my name is Ben
Hong and so today we are here to talk
about vue.js 101 for those of you that
have your laptop's out if you follow
this URL you will get actually like live
updates of the slides as I go through
them so that all helped you guys follow
through with that said let's get started
so the first question obviously is what
is view Jas and you know the short and
simple answer is that it's another
client-side framework in sort of the
massive ecosystem that we already have
but it's it's special and so in order to
give a little context with that we're
gonna kind of step back a little bit and
when client-side framework were starting
to get really popular this is around
time I started getting back into
front-end development there was a sort
of issue of like there are so many to
choose from that before you knew it you
know
they were sort of running jokes already
about how often we were coming out with
new tools or frameworks for JavaScript
and it kind of became a bear but even in
this sort of massive ecosystem this guy
named Avenue decides you know he is
gonna build its own as well so he
originally worked at Google creative
labs and so had some work working with
meteor working with angular as well and
then after angular one in particular and
after working with it for a while he he
felt like you know what I can build
something better like most of our and so
his brainchild is Vijay s all by his
little lonesome and so there's this
popular xkcd comic you know with the
fact that every time there's a problem
instead of trying to fix the original
one we come up with some new new
solution for it but the UJS is special
in this regard and I would say that its
exception to this and so obviously the
question is what makes it so special
and so let by to illustrate this we're
gonna compare it to so the two behemoths
in the client side favorite industry so
we have angular particularly we talk
about angular 1 just because that's
around the time that view came out so
obviously developed and maintained by
Google it was really easy to get
something prototype up and running
really quickly however the problem was
that a lot of it was like a mat there
was a lot of magical angular syntax so
when it came to actually debugging what
was going on you it was a pretty high
learning curve just to kind of get into
the weeds of what was going on
performance wasn't the best with angular
one at the time as well and it was
really opinionated on how you should
build your app and that's not
necessarily a bad thing even though I
put it as a con however it does restrict
teams as far as like opting out or
opting into certain technologies and so
it's just something that angular had
that others didn't
as far as react goes so as he developed
by Facebook and was recently granted the
MIT license which was a big win for the
open-source community and it had great
performance due to the proliferation of
the virtual Dom and so now most people
nowadays know what that is because of
react and the other thing I liked a lot
about react is that you got a lot better
at vanilla JavaScript really quickly
because unlike angular which provides
you a lot of sort of magical commands to
do things you had to write everything
well you have to write a lot of things
from scratch when it came to react on
the other hand the downside to this is
that there was a really high learning
curve as far as getting started if you
were not a JavaScript developer to start
it could it was a lot to deal with as
far as like oh used to configure web
pack and then have to do this bundler
and then you know it so yeah that was
kind of a rough start with react and as
well as a result this is really
unfriendly to non JavaScript developers
especially if people come to like the
design world where their HTML CSS
specialist and they want to kind of come
in and help out with the default
template language of JSX is just you
can't just you know post paste regular
markup into it you have to like convert
it into JavaScript friendly syntax and
you know the other thing especially in
this earlier days because there was such
a high pace of development you never
knew when you upgraded your react
whether or not certain dependencies or
libraries were going to break as a
result so this you know sort of like one
of the things I was a cautionary tale as
far as like when using an upgrading
react now view on the other hand it has
no corporate influence and clearly open
source so the the reason this is a pro
is because unlike Facebook they had the
parse developer platform at one point
and one day they decide to just close it
down and that that hurt a lot of
different people whereas so with view we
know there's open source and that we
don't have to worry about a company
deciding because it's in its best own
best interest that they're going to like
shut it down so that's a nice pro about
it after working I've worked a lot with
it react a little bit with angular and
as far as I can tell it really does take
the best of both worlds and brings them
together and a huge Pro because you know
we have developers on our team that
again are not JavaScript experts and in
fact tried to touch it as little as
possible so the fact that it doesn't a
liate non JavaScript developers is a
huge plus for us as well as you would
I'll show you shortly and as far as
performance goes it's pretty much on par
if not better than react as some tests
have shown and almost most importantly
it's very flexible in accommodating how
you prefer to build your apps so for
example with you know angular IO types
of it is pretty much mandatory well view
doesn't force you to do that but if you
want to opt in there is official support
for typescript and you have those
options to pick
as you're going through your view app
and then of course we got to find a con
somewhere and so it does have a small
core team in comparison in a smaller
community however as far as the pace of
development I've seen them sort of build
all the core modules and libraries at a
pretty great pace so with that said I'm
sure of you're like you know as a saying
goes show me don't tell me
so let's go ahead and jump right into
the essentials of view so I'm going to
open this code pen right here and okay
so actually you know what I'm gonna use
this one instead so as you can see here
we have a flat HTML file this nothing
fancy about it right here you can see
I've had a basic just view app
configuration so normally when it has
like reacting angular nowadays most
people are used to this process where
you have to install the command line
tool and then you have to run web pack
and everything well as the slide and
sort of as I mentioned it's really as
easy as including jQuery so we're gonna
go ahead and copy it and just like you
would normally you just you have your
script tag and your page or CDN and now
once I attach the element hook you can
see here now that when I update the HTML
syntax does it so in like two lines of
code you see here we have a functional
view app running on granted you know
you'll want to event to get Babel to
transpile and everything but as far as
like getting something up and running
it's it's up and running as you can see
here for those aren't familiar with it
view does use the much tests in tax kind
of out of the box I'm you can certainly
change it to other signifiers if you
want but as you can see that was pretty
simple to do okay so for those of us
that aren't as familiar with client-side
frameworks so what I did there is let's
let's kind of take a step back and break
it down so the first thing we do is we
initialize an instance right I'm
declaring an app variable here and
initializing view nothing too special
and so we're going to abstract it
a little bit out for those that aren't
as submitted with JavaScript and we're
going to pretend we're planning a trip
and so we have this new trip and we're
gonna do we're gonna map out all like
the important details we want to do on
this trip so you know we want to go to
you know Diagon Alley and then you know
within our luggage we're gonna carry you
know these various things and then when
it comes of things to do these are the
things we want to do when it comes to
our trip and so the first thing we have
to do with any good configuration is
determining as we said the destination
and so in your configuration object this
is determined by you know Al which
stands for element and it takes a CSS
selector which we which the best
practice is to use an ID so that you
only have one instance of your app
running on any given page once you do
that then your luggage ultimately
becomes your is your data object and
this is what we're going to reach into
to reference as we throughout as we work
in our HTML template and as far as our
things to do this is ultimately our
methods block this is going to sort of
have enabled the app to do different
things according to what we want as we
define them so instead of so let's let's
take a look at this in action all right
so as you can see here once again I have
very simple you know again just straight
HTML nothing special about this and I've
already included the script here and
I've copied over the code that we had in
the slide example and so let's go ahead
and start wiring some of the stuff up so
is see so we have our static name
so again just using much testing tax
okay so something's not working right
and so what's going on 99% of the time
it's because you forgot to attach your
app which is what I didn't do as you can
see here the element is diagonally and
we don't have an element on here that
has that so once I attach that on
voila now you have your data running so
I'm gonna go ahead and let's go ahead
and swap in the mess with data here
all right great and then I'm gonna go
ahead and fill these yep let me go back
so it slides calm slash Ben codes n /
UJS 101 the essentials / live good okay
jump back alright okay you're welcome
so as we can see here I'm going to go
ahead and wire up a couple more things
so we have our wallet here and we'll
reference this alright so as you can see
here we have hooked up our basic Harry
Potter world app with the data model
here with you alright so before we can
move on to the next stuff that was more
interesting we need to talk about
directives and so directives are the one
part of you that is kind of magical and
for those of you the bots and angular
it's gonna be you guys don't know what
I'm talking about
ultimately what they are are view
specific methods that allow you to a
comment accomplish common goals that
abstract away sort of the implementation
piece and so here you have a list of
like sort of common directives that we
have in view the most popular ones and
the ones we're going to cover are the
ones on the left hand side and so as you
can see they're all prefixed with the V
dash in order to ensure that it doesn't
collide with anything else in your
application so starting with the V
if-else elsif and V show they these are
directives that ultimately toggle the
visibility of your elements but there is
one key distinction between them the V
if and the VLC if they actually destroy
the element on the page and like they
made sure all the event handlers and
everything are eliminated whereas V show
is really just a CSS toggle
and so to show you that real quick we
have our little parchment here so I'm
gonna go ahead and actually make you up
an element inspector all right so here
is our parchment right here and then so
if I do V V if and I just declare false
you will see that the element is
completely gone from there it's nowhere
to be found it's actually destroyed Dom
element and thus nowhere is not the
you're not able to reference it on the
other hand if you use the v-- show false
you'll notice that the truthers
and you do the false it actually just
uses a CSS to toggle the hiding it so
actually let me switch as you can see
here style display:none and then again
just actually I realize those in another
iframe when I just showed you this
earlier so V else on the other the if on
the other hand it's completely gone and
so those are the main differences
between them usually if you're gonna
toggle frequently as far as like
visibility goes then you're gonna want
me show otherwise V if is the most
common one you're gonna be using for
kind of removing and adding elements
back into the Dom there is this tweet I
saw by Sam who works at Google and it
says a 97% or 99% of software
development in one requirement is that a
user should be able to view view a list
of items and so luckily view has a
directive for that and that is v4 and as
you can see here in this simple example
it takes what you would normally have to
very tediously like right out by hand if
you were sort of doing this right here
and it just condenses it all down into
one simple block and so like like we do
before let's go and show you the live
example with this one right here so let
me go ahead yeah sure
so in the instance of let's say you have
I don't know three different banners and
you want the first one to show up in the
event you have an error but you want a
default banner to show otherwise so that
could be a simple exempt us off the top
of my head they send you just you have a
default element that you would normally
show and then you have condition to
toggle it depending on yes that's right
so right so you would have your if
statement as we had before so let me go
ahead let me see if I can do this live
all right so in this case we have this
parchment true and okay here this okay
so as you can see here I have two Dom
elements here and me condense this down
did it too much sorry hang on a sec okay
so I have two Dom elements here we have
our V if true show this parchment
otherwise show the other parchment so
now if I toggle this to false there it
is it's not styled properly but you can
see it right here so that's essentially
what's going on and then you can have V
else--if to show again additional
conditions just like to continue that
chain of logic if you'd like yes so in
this case yeah so like again this is uh
I don't know let's see uh wallet
galleons is greater than 20
okay so in this case wallet galleons is
not 20 because I set it at 12 so I'm
gonna treat that so now you can see now
you have here let me get this color
white so that is there you go so you can
see here it went through the first vfvf
condition which I declared a false
immediately then went to check the
second one to make sure if the Y
galleons was greater and since it was
then it showed this and then in the
event it's not then it will run all the
way down to the final one yeah ideally
you want your Fiat to be the first one
and then else it's all in the middle and
then your else at the very bottom it is
really sort of like for legibility it
helps to kind of keep it in that order
yeah
I believe it will break we can test it
right yeah yeah I don't think it'll run
yeah it looks like it does have to be in
a specific order yep
any other questions sorry yeah always
feel free to flag me in case you have a
question I'd get little heads down
sometimes okay so let's go back right we
were talking about the V for loop so
here we have sort of our galleons and so
earlier you saw that what I did was I
manually went in there to change the
lists itself and again for like three
items it's kind of not a big deal but in
the event this was you know again like a
list of 100 items this would get pretty
unbearable pretty quickly so let's go
ahead and refactor this using the v4 so
essentially you put your v4 on the HTML
element that you actually want to repeat
so we're gonna v4 and we're gonna
declare we want the okay so I have an
object so the syntax here is we have the
amount so you have your value and your
key which is the label and in wallet so
I'll explain this real quick what I'm
doing in a second okay so as you can see
here in my data object I have this
wallet object here and so what I'm
telling you to do is let me just put
numbers here is I'm telling for for
every item in wallet I want you to go
ahead and output these labels so again
we're gonna use the the mustache syntax
and that's it now you've sort of
eliminated all that redundancy and very
clean very semantic and you know what's
going on yeah
yep yeah so there are so those are one
of the advanced hop was you can have add
filters like custom filters for like
highlighting title casing you could also
this is so I wonder between the
handlebar syntax it it should be
actually rendering the actual inline
JavaScript so you could write inline
JavaScript in there if you wanted to to
like do that but obviously there are
cleaner ways of doing that in view okay
computer methods is different from data
yeah that's something that we will get
to in like the 201 but that's how to do
is sort of how data is being updated as
like the most of the life cycle
yeah but filters are just again in her
case you would do something like title
case and so label would pass through
this this filter that I'd build called
title case it would take the string and
it would like make the first case first
letter uppercase so be an example there
are some built-in ones but most of the
time we're gonna be building your own as
far as I'm aware
so again yeah another popular one would
be like thing and we'll just want to be
like currency if you want to turn just
like US dollars that's another way
okay so let's I see we were okay so now
that we've covered v4 let's talk about V
pine so all this data manipulation is
nice but a lot of times what we need to
do is actually update HTML attributes
and so view provides us a directive V
bind as you can see here the long way of
writing in is V - pine with a semicolon
and then whatever attribute you want
whether its source title doesn't matter
I'll be using the shortcut way and this
is probably the way you're gonna be
seeing in most commonly in code bases
where you just prefix the attribute you
want with the semicolon and then and
then after that it's gonna be rendering
JavaScript so to show you what I mean by
that we are go so I've already defined
in the css3 different classes for
the wallet so you can see a galleon
sickles nuts and they just get a color
very simple yeah sure yep right here so
this I should so it's bound by actually
JavaScript syntax and so as far as just
when you do a for loop normally what you
want to do is in an object you yeah
normally it does like the value but in
case you want to include the key then
the key always comes second in that so
like the standard JavaScript syntax if
I'm not mistaken so that's the reason
why it's a mount label and that label
amount because normally you're looping
through the value and not necessarily
the key yep okay so we were about to
alright we're gonna show you V bind so I
want to attach any class to each of
these l eyes but I don't again I want to
do that in a dynamic way and not have to
manually code it so I'm going to go
ahead and declare the be bind class and
I'm going to just okay so the moment you
attach the V bind the stuff in between
your string is actually going to be
inline JavaScript it's not actually
parsing like a real string so in this
case I'm going to use label that I
referred to sort of in this loop and as
you can see here immediately
it applies the various classes that I
want for it galleons tickles nuts all
they're all done and so you can do this
with you know again any HTML attribute
you know styles and you can do some
really cool things as far as dynamic
updating and we'll have some fun sort of
code sandbox things for you guys to try
later on any questions about be binds so
far okay yes pretty straightforward
finally we have the V on and so as in
addition to manipulating data and your
attributes you obviously want to attach
event handlers and so you have your V on
and then there's a bunch of your
JavaScript events
so the shorthand for this one for Veon
is your at symbol and that's what we'll
be using moving forward and so I'm gonna
go back to the button here and so for
this when the button is clicked I want
to attach this method fired confetti
that I wrote down here so on click fire
and study and then I cook it magic yay
and that's all that's all there was to
it and so again very clean easy to read
easy to track ah
so right here the dooty dooty why did I
lose it right here so I did the app
click fire confetti and so this is
something that I already sort of set up
beforehand it's just like a JavaScript
function that again creates the confetti
so that's V on and those and then let's
see ah I have one more V model so this
is views pretty much single way of using
two-way data-binding and obviously as
far as state management goes for those
are aren't familiar with it single
statement single state flow is pretty
much like sorry unidirectional data flow
is sort of the popular method now but
the model does allow us to use two-way
data-binding if we need it and so back
to the button example we it's as simple
as typing V model equals and then the
data attribute that you want to tie to
and in this case would be message so now
sorry do I have it twice
oh hey left it in there when I was
playing around with it you're right okay
so yes so the V model here as we can see
is now is showing in the placeholder is
actually showing the value of this is
easy and then when you update it with
whatever you want you can see it's just
dynamically updating the data property
on the page so very simple very powerful
and just good to know
so there are event buses and view X
which is centrally used version of redux
and that is a topic we'll get into in
another time date okay so with that said
let's take a quick five minute break for
anyone you need to grab a drink or you
know yeah I get something to eat and
then for those with laptops you want to
try the final coding exercise we're
gonna have I'm gonna have some basic
tasks for you to just sort of practice
what we just went over and then yep so
we'll be back into the five minutes okay
so uh I thought it's best to obviously
give people some practice with what
we're learning so you guys can actually
reinforce what you're doing so as far as
the exercise we have just like your
basic for those who watch we can more to
basic Rick generator this is the final
product as you can see here I can go
ahead and type whatever I want in this
text input it'll update these down in
here and then in the event I want to you
know copy an image link from somewhere
it'll also paste in and then so let's
just do that real quick let's try let's
do strawberries and then I can click and
reposition in his face so that's so this
is what we'll sort of be building sort
of for the rest of the Meetup and so
your first so this is your starter pen
and your first task will break it up
into segments and so go ahead and
replace the pickle word with the actual
I cook it up with the noun probably the
same data and and make sure that's wired
up correctly so that you are dynamic and
dynamically updated in the text box as I
showed you earlier and then also go
ahead and wire up the background image
and so I'll give you guys a couple
minutes to kind of take a look and see
what you can do
and then I'll cut along with you guys
afterwards so I won't there were too
much of the wall okay for those of you
to keep work working on your own go
ahead and keep going I'm gonna go ahead
and start coding so everyone else
doesn't have a laptop can follow along
so our first task we have for this
exercise is to replace pickle with a
dynamic data property now so as we can
see here we have configured a new app
however we had not lifted up yet so
we're gonna hook up the main div class
with app ID and then the next thing
we're going to do is let's go ahead and
write something in here is this color
like cucumber and the solution of this
if you're gonna use our mustache syntax
and we're gonna like now in here now we
have dynamic dynamic property updating
within our HTML template pretty
straightforward task number two was to
none hook up this input to dynamically
update the non-property so all we got to
do is going to find this input and its
input noun right here and this is
anything so we're gonna use two-way
data-binding for this one go to the view
model and we're gonna attach it to our
noun property and finally we wanted to
tie in the background image this is
probably the this is the trickier part
so let's go ahead and first define a
background image or I think actually in
the exercise I felt like if you're all
and so what I'm gonna do now is I'm
gonna go to see it is okay so the reason
I put this in line now Craig it normally
with most your HTML code you're not
gonna actually put your your Styles in
line the reason we're doing it in this
case is because we're gonna make use of
the V bind property to make this dynamic
and so what we want to do here is we're
going to so this piece right here is
pickle so we're gonna go ahead and you
know just make sure it works in the face
of them here and so now we have to
rewrite this and so the gotcha
with dynamic styles with distribution is
that it needs to be written in an object
syntax so this is what is more like
JavaScript JavaScript styling so your
background image now has to be in this
channel case and then because it's
trying to interpret the URL as a
variable you have to actually wrap it in
a string so this is a string and we're
going to add something to it shortly
okay so this looks a little convoluted
but I will show you what I'm doing a
second all right
there's it uh URL plus oh there's a one
more tick here yeah you're probably
right well this is why we have I figure
out the solution just to reference it in
case something went wrong
right
yeah this is dissonant allergic okay so
once again less let me let me one line
this so this is easier for everyone to
read so as you can see here were we're
using the V vine on the style and once
again it's going to take in a JavaScript
object that's a post your normal like
inline CSS where you have your normal
casing so we have our object right here
that's marked here and here and then we
declare our CSS property we want to
change this background image and then
once again because URL we want to as a
string and not as like to interpret out
the variable we have to wrap this in
single single quotations and then we
again we drop in our data object right
here in image URL and then we close it
off with the press intact with the
string here and then close it off with
the object and now you have now we have
connected to image URL to it and then
similar to the noun 1 we are going to
attach a D model to the background image
and that we call the image URL so once
again let's go ahead and do that shot if
I paste in the strawberry URL there you
go that's how that works so again the
most convoluted piece of this is the
Gotcha which I failed to mention earlier
again when you're doing dynamic styling
it has to be a JavaScript CSS syntax not
straight CSS it's straight CSS any
questions about that so far
Phyllis
yep
yep I had an issue with that at one
point button maybe because of let's find
out
I do like yes
[Music]
so this is possible transpiling issue
possibly so the other way we could do
this actually if we wanted to make this
even easier on ourselves
let's declare it down here where we
don't have to deal with that up there so
you have this is an object that's good
so a six template literals do work in
some cases I think in this particular
case because of all the different mush
test syntax and everything running
around it's a little bit on the
complicated side so I will make a note
to come up with a demo that actually
works with that and get back to you on
that but that's a great question okay
any other questions for the first
exercise so going back now we're gonna
move on today we're going to use our
directives and methods that we can
practice doing that and so in the final
example that we have here you're able to
toggle the menu up here make it hidden
and show so you're welcome to use
whatever directives you'd like to use to
accomplish that but that is your first
task and for those of you that a little
bit more gung-ho then you can go ahead
and try and write your own method that
then allows you to dynamically update
the position of this face depending on
where you need it to be on the image and
it's gonna be as you can see here and
it's just a preview distribution it's
gonna be a little bit tricky because you
have to we're gonna using a V bind on
your style and updating some of the
absolute position of it so if that said
let me cue up the slides again and I
will leave I'll leave the JSP saw so in
case anyone wants a reference if they're
trying to figure it out
if there are any questions please let me
know you know and you around like back
tick okay go great
yeah that's an awesome fine you had a
yeah had them too early
yep yes yep so as far as yeah that's a
great question
as far as best practices go you should
turn it into a function it returns a new
object every time as far as like state
management goes for the purpose of this
exercise you don't have to do that it
should just work out of the box if you
prefer to as a complaint object but Evan
did recently come out with standards
people having checked out the docs he
has saga that I she came out which is
pretty great and he essentially has
these rule categories where he
prioritizes certain things that you
really should be doing any of you have
this best practices and that's one of
them which is so he said like he would
prefer that we all use functions but for
the purposes of like illustrating sort
of everything's working I kept
everything object to say
correct yep mm-hmm yep absolutely
great question all right so let's again
for those working feel free to continue
on suicide okay okay sorry I have the
final one up switch over okay
so our first test was to toggle this
piece and since we're gonna be toggling
on and off pretty frequently what I'm
going to do is I'm going to use the V
show directive again gonna use BL B if
that would have worked as well so for
the side menu here which is the wrapper
for this I like it
you'll do the V show and in this case
again let's make sure it works V show
false great so we're gonna do that we're
gonna have a dynamic property to manage
the state put up and so we're gonna call
that you know show side menu and I'm
gonna call that default doctor too and
so just to make sure that works we're
going to then say okay so side hey there
you go it works so now we want to attach
our event handler to the button in order
to toggle that back and forth so we're
gonna go look for that button and that
is right here
the pocket button and you do this on a
single line so that's easy to do so in
this event what we want to do we want to
listen for a click event right so at
click very simple and so I'm going to
show this the in line way and then we'll
refactor it back out so the easiest way
for us to do this is we're gonna say
okay show side menu and we're gonna make
it equal to nachos
yeah I can toggle back and forth so this
works okay for obviously shorter
inline JavaScript that you don't need
anything complicated for but let's just
say for instance this was like you know
a few lines of code that we need to
refactor so in this case you would just
declare your methods config and so we're
gonna call this you know toggle side
menu that's our function and then we're
going to go ahead like this right here
drop it in then we're gonna do toggles
side right this should work right
that doesn't yes that's right
it needs context and we need this so can
you do like this is fine okay so now you
we have positive on and off and again
this would have worked just for picking
it'll be if again since we're talking
about or not frequently and we don't
want to actually have to recreate
everything all at once we took on
visibility thing we show is the more
appropriate one to use okay so we're
gonna spend let's say about five to ten
minutes sort of talking about the
challenge number ways of doing this and
I just sort of thought I'd come up with
a fun one so in the final exercise again
what we could do is we could click
anywhere and it would update the
position of Rick's face and so what I'm
gonna do is go ahead and just kind of
walk you through it it's like putting in
my complicated a little bit so
ultimately what we're doing here is
we're updating this template wrapper and
so I've absolutely positioned this whole
thing and I've declared the top and the
left with the Y and X data properties
and then you have to attach the pixels
just to give it a dimensions so that it
actually knows where to move and then
I'll explain why I define the width here
in a second so as far as what's going on
you'll see here that in the image
wrapper here we have a click right and
this click calls the update position
function you scroll down to update
position you'll see that what I do is I
go ahead and I start by ok so when you
do a click event and you declare a
function on it you get past an event
parameter as part of it you don't have
to use it but in the case we do and so
ignoring these first these top two lines
essentially you'll see that I'm
dynamically updating the x and y
properties with your event Kline Xing
client Y and that's something you get
for free when you as when you click on
something so the client X tells you
where your mouse is from the X and then
Y essentially and then the reason why we
have this piece right here as far as the
wrapper width is because originally when
I set this up the it anchors the div at
the corner of it so essentially you'll
notice that Rick's face is actually
where my clicker is and so in order to
position my mouse at there I had to
essentially do a little bit of math as
far as like sort of fixing it based on
the width of the day of so that energy
clicks on it
whereas like just to show you if I take
these two things off you'll notice now
I'm at the corner which is fine like for
demo purposes like but I kind of wanted
to figure that out so that's why I have
the wrapper with calculation here and I
just defined the width in line on the
HTML in order to access access the
property with style with so and that
allows me to click and then his face
will be dead center on anywhere I click
anyone have any questions about that
ok
solid
let's unpack to the sides alright so as
you guys can see there's a quote by Sir
Dresner that I really liked in her
course and she says you know view gives
me what I want when I need it and then
it gets out of my way and that's how I
feel a lot when I work with you I'm like
oh I want to hide something on my okay
be if this all right now I'm moving on
to something else
well we recently built a an app and
react native and so I can just tell you
from personal experience just the hassle
of trying to go back and rewrite
functions to either remap things or
reduce things it can it can be a bit
much as far as management and so view is
just it's really clean semantically and
you know I just it's been great because
of that uh so you know Congrats
everybody we've essentially walked
through three view applications in
little over an hour and so you've gotten
some practice as well but of course
there's more this is just the 101 bare
minimum essentials for getting something
up and running as you can see here as
some of you actually pointed out there
are still a lot of things to talk about
as far as computer properties filters
props mix-ins I mean they're just a
whole slew of things that view also
provides for you when you're building
your single page application and in the
future we'll be having talks regarding
these in the - one we're talking a bit
about the concepts and then we'll have
worked for specific talks to talk about
you know app architecture
testing managing Styles because
obviously managing styles in Java skips
is a hotly discussed topic in our realm
so we'll have a talk about that and of
course nowadays functional animation is
the big deal so view does a beautiful
job as far as managing those animations
and so we will talk about that as well
in the future and so as far as a sneak
peek at vue.js 201 I wanted you guys to
or Gary had suggested very sorry that's
right
Chris he suggested that we sort of show
you guys so whenever you work over the
meet zoom in if you guys do open a view
code base in the future
obviously people aren't working just
like a single HTML file and then like
writing everything in there that'd be
impossible to manage and you just get
out of hand really quick so I just want
to give you guys a sneak peek into 201
where we start talking about the like
view template file so you can see here
instead of like dot HTML gesture dot CSS
we have a dot view and it's comprised of
three blocks and so just to make a
little easier I'm gonna open BS code
real quick just show you guys it's
simple scaffold okay so it's comprised
of that your view file is gonna be
comprised of three blocks whenever
you're looking at it template pretty
straightforward this is your HTML
template basic rule of thumb at the
moment I don't think they've done this
indeed yet but you can only have it can
only return a single a single element
you can't have two next to each other I
think Pete react has already fixed this
but I don't think you has yet and then
obviously your script here is your basic
JavaScript as you're used to in your
HTML and this is your style block for
writing your CSS some cool things about
the style block just to mention is that
you can actually define the type of
language you'd like to use and it'll
actually you might need to install a
package or two but generally it's very
convenient to be able to just switch to
the if you're like oh I really like
stylize I'm just going to stylus you
don't have to do anything special
regarding that and even cooler is that
you can just add a scope to attribute to
your style tags and that will scope all
your Styles to that component which is
pretty cool and we'll talk more about
that in managing styles for view anyways
so yep so this is like your basic
architecture that you can see here and
you can see that they've broken out into
different components so this is like the
sneak peek here we've actually defined a
component to use here to-do list and
this will then essentially insert all
the mark-up from in here so I guess it's
pretty interesting as far as component
architecture goes I mean anyone working
with modern day client frameworks are
familiar with this but it's just you
know do you has this as well
so with that said yep idea yep that
allows you to scope things for example
again like a button component you might
want to scope the styles there instead
of having this bloated CSS file and so
again this is one of the reasons you
might have a global style so it's it's
nice from a performance standpoint just
to only give users what they need and
not just like this gigantic CSS file
exactly right which is pretty great and
okay so as additional resources the
vue.js Doc's are done remarkably well
Evan you and his team have done a great
job as far as documenting and providing
examples for what they do and as I
mentioned before there's a style guide
in case anybody missed it before and so
these are sort of essentially his like
best practices recommendations for when
you're writing a view app such as
something to keep in mind it's in as you
can see it's in beta so this is pretty
new and then as far as people who like
going through courses front-end masters
has an introduction to view course by
Sarah Dresner and she's awesome and so I
just went do that just kind of see what
she taught and definitely great one to
check out and then for those who like
sort of on-demand and you can like
download them udemy is a great option as
well you have a bunch of view J's
courses on there the one in by
Maximilian is the one I first took and
that's not kind of how I got into view
and but if you do go on udemy do not buy
them full price they always have coupon
codes to make them like ten dollars from
the original two hundred dollars so do
not buy them at full price and finally
there is a view jeaious discord channel
so feel free to join that it's totally
free with that said there's footnotes so
if case you want to check out Evan used
story and yep that's it